CÉSAR MOLTÓ MORILLA

VIDEO GAME PROGRAMMER

ABOUT ME

I am a video game programmer specialized in Gameplay Programming who loves creating interactive experiences that users find immersive, intuitive, and challenging.

I am passionate about technology, sports, and travelling. When I am not working or studying, I like to play competitive video games, watch movies, or do outdoor sports and martial arts.

SKILLS

C / C++ / C# / JAVA / GLSL / BLUEPRINTS (UE4 VISUAL SCRIPTING)

UNREAL ENGINE 4 / UNITY 3D / VISUAL STUDIO / ANDROID STUDIO

GAMEPLAY + AI PROGRAMMING / PHYSICS + GRAPHICS + VR PROGRAMMING

GIT / MERCURIAL / GITHUB / PERFORCE

TEAM WORK / AGILE METHODS / PROJECT MANAGEMENT

LANGUAGES

ENGLISH

Full Professional Proficiency | CAE (C1)

GERMAN

Elementary | A2 level

JAPANESE

Beginner | Around N5 level

SPANISH AND CATALAN

Mother tongue | Native level

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

EMAIL

cmoltomorilla@gmail.com

WEBSITE

https://cesarmolto.github.io

PHONE NUMBER

+34 620 893 530

SKYPE

srmolto

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF ALICANTE

SPAIN

Multimedia Engineering Degree

2016 - Present

· Specialization in Creation of Digital Entertainment.

• GPA: 7.73 / 10

ATHLONE INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY

IRELAND

Software Engineering Exchange Year (Erasmus K103)

2018 - 2019

• Specialization in Game Programming.

• GPA: 8.93 / 10

WORK EXPERIENCE

HANDY GAMES

WÜRZBURG, GERMANY

Game programmer intern

September 2020 - March 2021

- Testing and troubleshooting for bugs and stability as well as ensuring correct documentation.
- Implementation of game controller input and UI with C++ and a custom game engine.
- Collaborate closely with other programmers, designers, testers, and artists to make sure that the game application meets functional and performance requirements.

4FREAKSFICTION

REMOTE

Game programmer

October 2018 - September 2020

- Volunteer work at this junior enterprise for PC and Mobile game development.
- Coordinated code with other programmers to prototype and implement new gameplay features in Unity 3D; i.e., combat and interaction mechanics, player controls, etc...

PROJECTS

DODGEBALL MASTERS

Gameplay and Engine programmer, Project Manager

2019 - 2020

Supervised and programmed a dodgeball multiplayer game with 8 playable characters and +20 unique skills using C++ and OpenGL. **Source code:** https://github.com/Woko103/Dodgeball Masters

BATTLE TANK

Programmer and Designer

2019

Developed a head-to-head tank fight game with Al-controlled enemies, pathfinding, and an advanced control system in UE4.

More information: https://cesarmolto.github.io/battle-tank.html

BAT HUNTER TANUKI: THE REVENGE

Programmer and Designer

2018 - 2019

Programmed and designed a Japanese folklore-inspired game in one week for the 2 Buttons Jam 2018.

More information: https://cesarmolto.github.io/bat-hunter-tanuki.html

ROOM MAKER VR

Programmer, Designer, and Project Manager

2017 - 2018

Led a 4 people team in programming and designing a Virtual Reality scenario editor with Unity 3D and Oculus hardware.

More information: https://cesarmolto.github.io/room-maker.html